In this lesson, you'll
get a full overview of
how to set up both
a basic and advanced RAG
pipeline with Llama Index. We'll load
in an evaluation benchmark and use
TrueLens to define a set of
metrics so that we can benchmark
advanced RAG techniques
against a baseline, or basic
pipeline. In the
next few lessons, we'll explore each
lesson a little bit more
in depth. Let's first walk through
how a basic Retrieval
Augmented Generation pipeline works,
or a RAG pipeline.
It consists of three different components, ingestion,
retrieval, and synthesis.
Going through
the ingestion
phase, we first load in
a set of documents. For each document, we
split it into a set of text
chunks using a text splitter. Then for each
chunk, we generate an embedding
for that chunk using an embedding
model. And then for each
chunk with embedding, we offload it to
an index, which is a view
of a storage system such as a MacAndrew
database. Once the data is
stored within an index,
we then perform retrieval
against that index.
First, we launch a user
query against the index,
and then we fetch
the top K most similar chunks to the
user query. Afterwards, we take these
relevant
chunks, combine it with the
user query, and put it into
the prompt window of
the LLM in the synthesis phase. And this
allows us to generate a final
response. This notebook will walk
you through how to set up
a basic and advanced RAG pipeline
with Llama Index.
We will also use
TruEra to help set up an
evaluation benchmark so that we can
measure improvements against the baseline. For
this quick start,
you will need an
OpenAI API key. Note that for this
lesson, we'll use a set of
helper functions to get you
set up and running quickly,
and we'll do a deep dive into
some of these sections in the future lessons.
Next, we'll create a
simple LLM application using
Llama Index, which internally
uses an OpenAI LLM. In
terms of the data source, we'll
use the How to Build a Career
in AI PDF written by
Andrew Wright. Note that you
can also upload your own
PDF file if you
wish. And for this
lesson, we encourage you to
do so. Let's do
some basic sanity checking of what the
document consists of as
well as the length
of the document. We
see that we have
a list of documents.
There's 41 elements in there. Each item in
that list
is a document object. And
we'll also show a
snippet of the text for a given
document. Next, we'll merge these into
a single document because it helps with
overall text blending accuracy when using more
advanced retrieval methods
such as a
sentence window retrieval
as well as
auto-merging retrieval. The
next step here is to index
these documents and we can do
this with the vector
store index within Llama
Index. Next, we define
a service context object
which contains both the
LLM we're going
to use as well
as the embedding model
we're going to use. The LLM we're going to
use is GPT-3.5-Turbo from OpenAI, and
then the embedding model that we're going
to use is the HuggingFace BGESmall model. These
few steps show
this ingestion process right here. We've loaded
in documents, and then
in one line, "VectorStoreIndexOfFromDocuments," we're
doing the chunking, embedding,
and indexing under the hood
with the embedding model that
you specified. Next, we obtain
a query
engine from this index that
allows us to send
user queries that do
retrieval and synthesis against this
data. Let's try out our first
request. And the query is, what
are steps to take when finding
projects to build your experience?
Let's find out. Start small and gradually
increase the scope and complexity of your projects.
Great, so it's working.
So now you've set up
the basic RAG
pipeline. The next step
is to set up
some evaluations against this pipeline
to understand how well it performs, and
this will also provide the basis for
defining our advanced retrieval methods of
a sentence window
retriever as well
as an auto-merging retriever. In this
section, we use TrueLens to initialize
feedback functions. We
initialize a helper function, get feedbacks,
to return a
list of feedback functions to
evaluate our app. Here, we've
created a RAG
evaluation triad, which consists
of pairwise comparisons between the
query, response, and context. And so this
really creates three different evaluation
modules, answer relevance,
context relevance, and groundedness. Answer relevance
is, is the response
relevant to the query.
Context relevance is, is the retrieved
context relevant to
the query. And
groundedness is,
is the
response supported
by the context.
We'll walk through how to set this
up yourself in
the next few notebooks.
The first thing we
need to do
is to create set of questions
on which does has her occupation.
Here, we've pre-written the first 10, and we
encourage you to add to the
list. And now we have some evaluation questions.
What are the keys
to building a career in AI? How
can teamwork contribute to
success in AI? Etc. The first thing we
need to do is
to create a set
of questions on which to
test our application. Here, we've
pre-written the first 10,
but we encourage you to
also add to this list.
Here, we specify a fun
new question, what is the
right AI job for me? And
we add it to the eval questions
list. Now we can initialize
the TrueLens modules to begin our
evaluation process. We've initialized the TrueLens
module and now we've reset the database. We
can now initialize our evaluation modules. LLMs are
growing as a standard mechanism
for evaluating generative AI
applications at scale. Rather than
relying on expensive human
evaluation or set benchmarks,
LLMs allows us to evaluate our applications
in a way that
is custom to the domain in
which we operate
and dynamic to the changing
demands for our
application. Here we've
pre-built a ShuLens recorder
to use for this
example. In the recorder,
we've included the standard triad of evaluations for
evaluating regs. Groundedness, context
relevance, and answer relevance.
We'll also specify an
ID so that we can
track this version of
our app. As we experiment,
we can track new
versions by simply changing the app
ID. Now we can
run the query
engine again with the
TrueLens context. So what's happening
here is that we're sending
each query to our query
engine. And in
the background, the TrueLens recorder
is evaluating each of our queries
against these three metrics.
If you see some
warning messages, don't worry about it.
Some of it is system dependent.
Here we can see
a list of queries
as well as their
associated responses. You
can see the input, output, the
record ID, tags, and
more. You can also see the
answer relevance, context relevance, and
groundedness for each rub. In this
dashboard, you can see your evaluation metrics like
context relevance, answer relevance,
and groundedness,
as well as average latency, total
cost, and more in the UI.
Here, we see that the answer relevance
and groundedness
are decently high, but CloudTax
relevance is pretty low. Now let's see
if we can improve
these metrics with
more advanced
retrieval techniques like sentence window
retrieval as well as on emerging retrieval.
The first advanced technique
we'll talk about
is sentence window retrieval. This
works by embedding and retrieving single
sentences, so more granular chunks. But after retrieval,
the sentences are
replaced with a
larger window of
sentences around the original retrieved sentence.
The intuition
is that this allows for
the LLM to have more context
for the information retrieved in
order to better answer
queries while still retrieving
on more granular
pieces of information. So ideally improving
both retrieval as
well as synthesis
performance. Now let's
take a look at how to
set it up. First, we'll use
opening IGBT 3.5
Turbo. Next, we'll
construct our sentence
window index over
the given document.
Just a reminder that we
have a helper
function for constructing the sentence window
index over the
given document. and we'll do a deep dive in how
this works under the hood in the
next few lessons. Similar to before, we'll
get a query
engine from the sentence
window index. And now that we've
set this up,
we can try
running an example
query. Here the question is, how
do I get started on
a personal project in AI?
And we get back a response. Get
started on a personal
project in AI is first
important to identify scope the
project. Great. Similarly to before, let's try getting
the TrueLens evaluation context and try benchmarking
the results. So here,
we import the True recorder
sentence window, which is a pre-built
True Lens recorder for the sentence
window index. And now
we'll run the sentence
window retriever on top
of these evaluation questions and
then compare performance on
the RAG triad of
evaluation modules. Here we
can see the responses
come in as they're being
run. Some examples of
questions and responses. How
can teamwork contribute to
success in AI? Teamwork can
contribute to success in AI by
allowing individuals to leverage the expertise
and insights of
their colleagues. What's the importance of
networking in AI? Networking is
important in AI because it
allows individuals to connect with
others who have experience and knowledge
in the field.
Great. Now that we've
run evaluations for two
techniques, the basic
RAG pipeline, as well as the
sentence window retrieval
pipeline, let's get a leaderboard of
the results
and see what's going on. Here, we
see that general
groundedness is 8 percentage points better
than the baseline RAG pipeline. Answer
relevance is more
or less the same. Context relevance is
also better for the sentence window
primary engine. Latency is
more or less the
same, and the total
cost is lower. Since the groundedness
and context relevance are higher, but the total
cost is lower, we
can intuit that
the sentence window retriever is actually
giving us more
relevant context and more
efficiently as well. When
we go back
into the UI, we can see
that we
now have a comparison between the direct
query engine and the baseline, as
well as the sentence
window. And we can
see the metrics that we just
saw in the notebook displayed in
UI as well.
The next advanced
retrieval technique we'll
talk about is the auto-merging
retriever. Here we construct a hierarchy of
larger parent nodes with smaller child nodes that
reference the parent node.
So for instance we might
have a parent node of chunk
size 512 tokens, and underneath there are four
child nodes of chunk
size 128 tokens that link to
this parent node.
The auto-merging retriever
works by merging retrieved nodes into
larger parent nodes, which means
that during retrieval, if a parent
actually has a
majority of its
children nodes retrieved, then we'll replace the
children nodes with the
parent node. So this allows us
to hierarchically merge our
retrieved nodes. The combination
of all the child
nodes is the same text as
the parent node. Similarly to
the sentence window
retriever, in the next few
lessons, we'll do a bit
more of a deep
dive on how it
works. Here, we'll show
you how to set it up
with our helper functions. Here,
we've built the auto merging index,
again, using GPT 3.5
Turbo for the LLM, as
well as the BGE model
for the embedding model. We
get the query
engine from the
auto-merging retriever. And let's try running
an example query. How do I
build a portfolio of AI projects? In the
logs here, you actually see the merging
process go on. We're merging nodes
into a
parent node to basically retrieve the
parent node as opposed
to the child node. To
build a portfolio of AI
projects, it is important to
start with simple undertakings and gradually progress to
more complex ones. Great,
so we see that it's working.
Now let's benchmark results with TrueLens. We get
a pre-built TrueLens recorder on
top of our auto
merging retriever. We then run
the auto merging retriever with TrueLens
on top of
our evaluation questions. Here for each
question, you actually see
the merging process going on, such as
merging three nodes into the parent
node for the
first question. If
we scroll down just
a little bit, we see that for
some of
these other questions, we're also
performing the merging process.
Merging three nodes into a parent
node, merging one node
into a parent node. An example
question response pair is, what is
the importance of
networking in AI? Networking
is important in AI
because it helps in
building a strong professional
networking community.